

UMANG SINGH

User Experience Designer

PORTFOLIO

https://umangsingh27.github.io/

CONTACT DETAILS

Phone No.: +91 700 324 3370

singh.umang1997@gmail.com

LinkedIn: umangsingh123

PROFILE

Gender: Male

> Nationality: Indian

> Marital Status: Single

27th October, 1997 > DOB:

SOFTWARE SKILLS











Figma Adobe XD

Sketch

Adobe Adobe Illustrator Photoshop

SPECIAL TRAITS

- > Enhancing User Experience
- > Strong Analytical Skills
- > Planning & Strategic Thinking
- > Effective Communication Skills
- > Leadership Qualities
- > Result Oriented Focus

I am a learning enthusiast and a full-stack UX Designer, keen on upgrading my skill sets while creating innovative digital products. I have about 2 years of experience of solving complex problems with special interest in User Research and Designing UX for Digital Products.

EXPERIENCE

Winjit Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

May 2021 - Till Date: User Experience (UX) Designer

Stand Up India, Building Link, National Livestock Mission, Clients:

Docuverous, RBL Bank, BOB World, Sealcon, iTwo, Torrent Labs, Mint My Piece, SIDBI, Doxiva, C1 India.

Client Interaction, User Research, Competitive Analysis, Worked on:

> Concept Building, Ideation, IA, Task Flow, Wireframes, Mockups, Prototyping (Single-handedly, End-to-end)

"Rising Star" (Oct 2021) Award:

Mobiliya Tech - "SharedBatua" Live Project

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021 (5 Months) - Team Lead 6D UX Design Process, Fintech Ecosystem, User Research, Competitive Analysis, Persona, Journey Map, Ideation, Conceptualization, Information Architecture, Wireframes, Mockups, Prototyping, Usability Testing

Snapper Future Tech - "CredibleMe" Live Project

Nov 2020 - Mar 2021 (5 Months)

6D UX Design Process, User Research, Competitive Analysis, Persona & Journey Map, Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototyping

College Design Team, Event Promotion & Mngt.

2018 - 2020

Created Logos, Posters, Banners & Digital Artworks for events Actively Organised New Year Eve - DJ Party, Sponsored by Presto

EDUCATION

Master of Design in User Experience (UX/UI)

2020 - 2022 : Chitkara University, Punjab Pursuing Sem 4 [Sem 1, 2 & 3 : CGPA - 9.42] Currently working on my Thesis for Sem 4

Bachelor of Commerce (Honors)

2017 - 2020 : University of Calcutta, Kolkata, WB

ISC (XII)

2015 - 2017 : Little Star High School, West Bengal

ICSE (X)

2003 - 2014: Don Bosco School, Liluah, West Bengal

COMPETITION & PROF. CERTIFICATION

Tata CliQ - ImaginXP Design-a-thon Competition Oct 2021

End-to-end designing of Career Counciling Mobile App - Career Wings Design Process: Empathise, Define, Ideate, Prototype, Test Result: Secured 7th Position (among 350+ candidates)

Google UX Design Professional Certificate

By Google - On Corsera Platform - Completed all 7 courses

Digital Skills: User Experience Certificate

By Accenture - On Future Learn Platform